<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inhales</title>
    <description>Captured breath from the Digital World
</description>
    <link>http://inhal.es/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://inhal.es/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 13:41:57 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 13:41:57 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>MOOCs, MIT and Magic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Great write up from Tony Bates from a recent conference at MIT. It provides a great overview of some of the topics covered during the talks, and also provides a really interesting overview of the structures and history of online learning and teaching at MIT. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his final observations he makes a couple of key points that I think apply to most  higher education institutions (and perhaps explains why online learning has been so bad for so long). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIT is still tied though to the lecture as the main means of delivery for online learning. In fact, the MIT students on the panel showed that they understand the need to adopt a different approach to online learning better than the faculty. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a fan of the lecture as a format - but not for ongoing teaching. Lectures should be seen as an effective  content delivery mechanism but it&amp;#39;s use should be limited. It should augment actual engagement with students, not be the form of engagement. Which perhaps says a lot about the next point too (emphasis added). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MOOCs are the consequence of lecture capture technology. This technology makes it easy to move teaching online, but without changing the design of the teaching. This usually results in &lt;strong&gt;information transmission becoming the primary pedagogy&lt;/strong&gt;, without addressing the many limitations of lectures, except the ability for asynchronous access, which is an important improvement on the ‘live’ lecture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information transmission is what I often refer to as Content First design and its what&amp;#39;s holding back higher education from really improving its overall learning and teaching practices. There&amp;#39;s a historic reason for this, the scarcity of information and knowledge, but that&amp;#39;s what the internet has changed. Instead we have information abundance which completely devalues and obsoletes information transmission as a primary pedagogy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tonybates.ca/2013/06/26/moocs-mit-and-magic/&quot;&gt;MOOCs, MIT and Magic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: photo credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/81295370@N00/211020203&quot;&gt;Science vacation&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;http://photopin.com&quot;&gt;photopin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&quot;&gt;(license)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 10:41:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/08/01/MOOCs-MIT-and-Magic.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/08/01/MOOCs-MIT-and-Magic.html</guid>
        
        <category>MOOC</category>
        
        <category>MOOCs</category>
        
        <category>online</category>
        
        <category>teaching</category>
        
        <category>MIT</category>
        
        <category>Bates</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Today’s march is a challenge to the rule of money</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This quote was linked to from Richard Hall&amp;#39;s post &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.richard-hall.org/2015/04/14/on-rage-against-learning-gain/&quot;&gt;on [rage against] learning gain&lt;/a&gt; which is a collection of quotes and snippets around the metrics being used in Higher Education. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular quote from John Holloway just stood out in stark contrast and immediately drew me in. It&amp;#39;s such a deep and insightful observation on the role of money in our social structure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we rage against the rule of money. Not against money itself, necessarily, because in the present society we need money to live. We rage rather against the rule of money, against a society in which money dominates. Money is a great bulldozer tearing up the world. It is an insidious force penetrating ever more aspects of our lives. Money holds society together, but it does so in a way that tears it apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one stage it seemed we had pushed the rule of money back, at least in areas like health and education. It was never really so, and for a long time we have seen the progressive re-imposition of the rule of money as the prime criterion for every decision. Now money has emerged in all its arrogance. That is what makes us so angry – the government has proclaimed openly “Money is king, bow low to the king!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rage, then, rage against the rule of money! As long as money rules, injustice and violence prevail – money is the breach between the starving and the food, the gap between the homeless and the houses. As long as money rules we are trapped in a dynamic that nobody controls and that is visibly destroying the possibility of human existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money seems all powerful, yet it is not. It is merely a form of social cohesion, and depends on our compliance. Say no, then. Do something else, do things in a different way. Refuse and create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– John Holloway. 2011. Today’s march is a challenge to the rule of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2011/mar/26/protest-rule-of-money&quot;&gt;Today’s march is a challenge to the rule of money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/pagedooley/3302646512&quot;&gt;Paper money&lt;/a&gt; by Kevin Dooley shared under a Creative Commons (BY) license&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 19:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/quote/2015/07/31/rule-of-money.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/quote/2015/07/31/rule-of-money.html</guid>
        
        <category>money</category>
        
        <category>rule</category>
        
        <category>rage</category>
        
        <category>cohesion</category>
        
        
        <category>quote</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Web We Have to Save</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having spent 6 years in Evin prison in northern Tehran,  this post from Hossein Derakhshan provides a unique perspective of the web and how it&amp;#39;s changed in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hyperlink was my currency six years ago. Stemming from the idea of the hypertext, the hyperlink provided a diversity and decentralisation that the real world lacked. The hyperlink represented the open, interconnected spirit of the world wide web — a vision that started with its inventor, Tim Berners-Lee. The hyperlink was a way to abandon centralization — all the links, lines and hierarchies — and replace them with something more distributed, a system of nodes and networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[...] Since I got out of jail, though, I’ve realized how much the hyperlink has been devalued, almost made obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rise of mobile and the &amp;quot;app&amp;quot; container it introduced has changed the way most people think about and interact with internet technologies. Now when most people discuss the web it&amp;#39;s through the lens of an app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypertext was, and still is, a quite radical way of approaching text. Our cultural traditions have embedded a &lt;em&gt;linear structure&lt;/em&gt; as the norm. The hyperlink disrupts that cultural narrative and for many people it&amp;#39;s uncomfortable so the contained app makes more sense to them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hossein&amp;#39;s observations about social media are really quite interesting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, these social networks tend to treat native text and pictures — things that are directly posted to them — with a lot more respect than those that reside on outside web pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps a sign of the &amp;quot;enclosure of the web&amp;quot; and the establishment of the Vectoral Class? Well maybe...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centralization of information also worries me because it makes it easier for things to disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the scariest outcome of the centralization of information in the age of social networks is something else: It is making us all much less powerful in relation to governments and corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I think this observation is pretty spot on. Despite the ability for the internet to engage and create spaces for real and meaningful interaction it isn&amp;#39;t. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web was not envisioned as a form of television when it was invented. But, like it or not, it is rapidly resembling TV: linear, passive, programmed and inward-looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/matter/the-web-we-have-to-save-2eb1fe15a426&quot;&gt;The Web We Have to Save&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/pFwRbV&quot;&gt;White House Vigil To Save Net Neutrality 11&lt;/a&gt; from Stephen Melkisethian&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 08:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/30/web-to-save.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/30/web-to-save.html</guid>
        
        <category>hyperlink</category>
        
        <category>link</category>
        
        <category>centralised</category>
        
        <category>centralized</category>
        
        <category>reading</category>
        
        <category>television</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Web We Need to Give Students</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an incredibly important post from Audrey Watters. She weaves together a narrative that speaks to a number of issues that are coming to define education and it&amp;#39;s relationship with technology. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is about student agency:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students have little agency when it comes to education technology — much like they have little agency in education itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And later she describes one of the key ideas embeded in  &lt;a href=&quot;http://umw.domains/&quot;&gt;Domain of One’s Own&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it is important to have one’s own space in order to develop one’s ideas and one’s craft. It’s important that learners have control over their work — their content and 
their data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why is any of this important?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The kids came in to the class with what I would call fair and average teen tech skills,” he said. “Lots of iPods, iPads, and laptops. Lots of Facebook and Instagram. But none of them had a presence online they were in control of before this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have your identity defined by someone else you&amp;#39;ve essentially ceded power and control. We simply can&amp;#39;t be reliant on a platform or a service to provide your voice, your persona, your representation, your self. We have to reclaim control. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One point I&amp;#39;m particularly interested in that Audrey makes is about this concept of &amp;quot;digital citizeship&amp;quot; and how it tends to be phrased as  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what students need to know in order to use technology “appropriately.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does &amp;quot;appropriately&amp;quot; mean? Who or what is it appropriate for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/bright/the-web-we-need-to-give-students-311d97713713&quot;&gt;The Web We Need to Give Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/5tNFGB&quot;&gt;#188 in explore&lt;/a&gt; from Ashley Rose&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 09:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/26/web-students-need.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/26/web-students-need.html</guid>
        
        <category>domain</category>
        
        <category>agency</category>
        
        <category>students</category>
        
        <category>control</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Co-Creating Curriculum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love this use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://storify.com/&quot;&gt;Storify&lt;/a&gt; almost as much as I love the post. I have so much love for efforts to empower students. This post touches on two important areas - by &lt;strong&gt;providing real choice&lt;/strong&gt; and the view of &lt;strong&gt;education as generative&lt;/strong&gt; rather than responsive. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://storify.com/Marnie_HW/co-creating-curriculum&quot;&gt;Co-Creating Curriculum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: JD Hancock &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/jdhancock/3948724485&quot;&gt;Get Creative!&lt;/a&gt; shared under a Creative Commons (BY) license&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 01:45:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/24/co-creating-curriculum.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/24/co-creating-curriculum.html</guid>
        
        <category>co-creation</category>
        
        <category>creativity</category>
        
        <category>model</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>generative</category>
        
        <category>choice</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital disruption and copyright</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I really struggled with this discussion between host Paul Barclay, Phillipa McGuinness and Lindy Morrison. It was an hour of circular argument that really failed to address copyright or digital disruption at all. What it did do was highlight the central fact that &lt;strong&gt;artists don&amp;#39;t get paid&lt;/strong&gt;. This isn&amp;#39;t new as Lindy clearly illustrates with tales of a career of dud deals, dodgy contracts and lack of protective legislation. Yet it&amp;#39;s downloading that cops all the blame, rather than sector that&amp;#39;s powered by exploitation. It&amp;#39;s the business of music that&amp;#39;s rotten - not the listeners, or the fans. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s the same old arguments of &amp;#39;theft&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;freeloading&amp;#39; that the topic of copyright seems to dwell on - both which are untrue and almost baseless. Sharing may breach copyright but it&amp;#39;s not theft. Nor are downloaders freeloaders - it&amp;#39;s proven they spend more on entertainment than any other section of society. How is downloading a song to sample any different from the historically OK instore experience with headphones in the corner? Seriously there is so much contradiction and incoherent argument that I&amp;#39;d suggest you just leave copyright out of this. It&amp;#39;s becoming a crutch for a crippled argument that no one is having. No one is disputing ownership, you&amp;#39;re disputing is who&amp;#39;s getting paid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This whole thing keeps getting framed as being about  copyright infringement- but it boils down to who&amp;#39;s not getting paid. And all the effort, whining and legislation about copyright simply reinforces the existing power structures and the status quo. It only ensures label and distributors make all the money. It does nothing to redistribute the wealth or address the inequality artists face in terms of getting compensated for their work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why not ask why a label gets to take 60% of every sale off the top. Why do they then get to take more to recover costs? Why is a performer offered little to no protection or payment? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, if you want to see digital disruption - use it to ensure fair compensation, fair ownership, fair representation. But let&amp;#39;s stop this copyright rot. Ok? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/radionational/programs/bigideas/digital-disruption-and-copyright/6603752&quot;&gt;Digital disruption and copyright&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 09:45:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/podcast/2015/07/22/Digital-disruption-and-copyright.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/podcast/2015/07/22/Digital-disruption-and-copyright.html</guid>
        
        <category>copyright</category>
        
        <category>equality</category>
        
        <category>payment</category>
        
        <category>paid</category>
        
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Office, messaging and verbs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A thought provoking post from Ben Evans. The central discussion is around productivity and how it is often achieved. What is laid out here is perhaps a different way to think about how businesses evolve and change, but not through Christensen&amp;#39;s disruptive innovation: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What killed those machines was not better, cheaper competitors but a completely different way to address the same underlying business need. Instead of hundreds of people recalculating insurance rates, the company bought a mainframe. The business need was being met, but the mechanism changed completely and the old tools disappeared. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve long been a critic of Christensen&amp;#39;s work - not that I disagree with it entirely, just that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;#39;s often viewed as the singular model for change and innovation&lt;/strong&gt;. So often cases are shoe-horned into the model&amp;#39;s narrative that are it becomes a case of historinics and where facts are severed in order to fit. Disruptive Innovation has so often become &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Procrustes&quot;&gt;Procrustean bed&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#39;ve come to view &lt;strong&gt;disruptive innovation as just only one model for change&lt;/strong&gt;, and it&amp;#39;s certainly not the only gig in town. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Evans lays out is perhaps another model in which to think about change and innovation. One that looks not at the tools and tasks, but in meeting the same needs by changing underlying systems and models being employed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The business need was being met, but the mechanism changed completely and the old tools disappeared. That is, the way forward for productivity is probably not to take software applications and document models that were conceived and built in a non-networked age and put them into the cloud, or to make carbon copies of them as web apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Evan&amp;#39;s focusses on software, my thinking is around education - how do can we change the &amp;#39;model&amp;#39; rather than just the tools we use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, those verbs get combined, broken apart, linked, created and removed as the tools change, the organization is changed by the tools and of course the underlying business itself changes. You don&amp;#39;t actually send email or make a spreadsheet - you analyze, delegate, report, confer, decide, track and so on. Or, perhaps, &amp;#39;what&amp;#39;s going on, what are we doing and what should we doing?&amp;#39; Each set of tools fixes that into a different pattern, but one should not look at that pattern and assume that that&amp;#39;s the way things must be done - that that&amp;#39;s what &amp;#39;real work&amp;#39; looks like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there&amp;#39;s space here for real change and innovative thought and practice. It might be what George Siemen&amp;#39;s calls unbundling - but perhaps it&amp;#39;s more remodelling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2015/5/21/office-messaging-and-verbs&quot;&gt;Office, messaging and verbs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: Robert Baxter, &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/fsWPFm&quot;&gt;Classroom&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 19:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/16/office-messaging-verbs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/16/office-messaging-verbs.html</guid>
        
        <category>innovation</category>
        
        <category>productivity</category>
        
        <category>model</category>
        
        <category>disruption</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mine.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post from Jonathan Rees is a response to Kate&amp;#39;s and is a defence of the lecture:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say what you want about lectures, but your lecture is unequivocally yours. You went to graduate school. You learned your discipline. You keep up on your reading so that you know what’s fresh. You convey that information to your students. They (hopefully) learn something of what you know. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t necessarily agree with all of Jonathon&amp;#39;s points but I would say that this defence of lectures is very much shaped by a &amp;quot;content-first&amp;quot; approach to education. This is the historical model of the university - as storehouse and generator of knowledge and information. It has shaped teaching practices in higher education but it is being challenged and disrupted by technology. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can understand the desire to fight obsolescence, but I think that energy would be better served by attempting to change the model. To shift the model from &amp;quot;content-first&amp;quot; to an &amp;quot;activity-first&amp;quot; model. One that values &lt;em&gt;teaching&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;interaction&lt;/em&gt; over content. Shifting the source of value is difficult - but I think its the best way to truly fight obsolence. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://moreorlessbunk.net/technology/mine/&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Mine.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hdwallpaperpc.com/preview-wallpaper/Finding_Nemo_Seagull_Bird_CG_108482/resolution_1920x1080&quot;&gt;Finding Nemo Seagull&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 09:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/16/mine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/16/mine.html</guid>
        
        <category>lectures</category>
        
        <category>content</category>
        
        <category>content first</category>
        
        <category>activity first</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What would Stampy do?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love this post from Kate. Lectures are an incredibly touchy subject in Higher Education and they tend to polarise people. They hate them or they love them. This polarity of opinions means that there&amp;#39;s very little middle ground on which to stand for those who sit somewhere in between. This post carves some space out for the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part in particularstrikes a balance between the affordances and costs of online and traditional lectures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The university lecture is the city where all faiths converge. Until we work out how to make online content as updatable and responsive as a live presentation, then investment in video production is just being added to capital investment in buildings and their maintenance, salaries and on-costs for the permanent staff, and quality assurance procedures for both domestic and international students, all cohering around the idea that content is delivered not found, and delivering content matters more than other forms of teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She also carves out space between the arguments between staff and students:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means understanding that just as we measure staff contact time as the tip of an iceberg of preparation and consultation, so we should expect students to calculate the opportunity cost of showing up at least in terms of travel and work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think its very easy to look at the cost component of staff time for lectures, but when was the last time we factored in the costs for students in those equations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comments below the post are also worthy of a read as there&amp;#39;s plenty of great questions, reponses and knowledge apparent in their. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://musicfordeckchairs.com/blog/2015/07/09/what-would-stampy-do/&quot;&gt;What would Stampy do?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/jordanshapiro/2015/05/31/this-is-what-you-should-be-asking-about-stampys-minecraft-videos/&quot;&gt;This Is What You Should Be Asking About Stampy&amp;#39;s Minecraft Videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 08:40:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/16/what-would-stampy-do.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/16/what-would-stampy-do.html</guid>
        
        <category>stampy</category>
        
        <category>lectures</category>
        
        <category>costs</category>
        
        <category>students</category>
        
        <category>middle ground</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Legitimising the Grapevine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Great post from Mark Drechsler on &lt;em&gt;Online Organisational Networking Environments&lt;/em&gt; like &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.yammer.com/&quot;&gt;Yammer&lt;/a&gt;. Having just come off a series of workshops across our campuses I&amp;#39;ve heard echo of the same phrases too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Nobody tells anyone anything around here’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Communication is always crap in this place’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Would have been nice if my manager had told me &lt;whatever&gt; rather than having to hear it from the grapevine’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet I dont think I could ever articulate a solution as well as what Mark has put together which is essentially about building a community. It&amp;#39;s much less about the dos and donts and more about the why&amp;#39;s and hows.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People need to know &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; to be part of the community;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People need to &lt;strong&gt;choose&lt;/strong&gt; to participate;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People need to know how to &lt;strong&gt;access the right information&lt;/strong&gt; for them; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The organisational culture needs to be one which makes &lt;strong&gt;peer sharing of information just as valid&lt;/strong&gt; as ‘top down’ sharing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think sharing really is the key message here. Institutions and organisations have to get beyond this concept of control around information. Embrace and encourage sharing and if needed give them hints about what to share:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sharing updates about what you or your team have been working on;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sharing relevant information (including links to external articles) that are of relevance to the community; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asking questions that the community might know the answer to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.markdrechsler.com/?p=1210&quot;&gt;Legitimising the Grapevine&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timklapdor/8595454120/in/photolist-fbkyuB-e6xX3Q-fbzQxy-fbSHwy-fbzR3Q-fbkyXg-fbkAsH-fbzS97-fbkBpK-e6xUWL-fbzBk5-e6sh4F-fbkkWi-fbzAry-fbzALU&quot;&gt;Vineyards&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Klapdor&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 07:25:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/16/legitimising-the-grapevine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/16/legitimising-the-grapevine.html</guid>
        
        <category>social</category>
        
        <category>network organisations</category>
        
        <category>sharing</category>
        
        <category>communication</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
