<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inhales</title>
    <description>Captured breath from the Digital World
</description>
    <link>http://inhal.es/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://inhal.es/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 12:53:06 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 12:53:06 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Leave I Out of Feedback</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a simple article with a simple premise for giving better feedback:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When giving or responding to feedback, avoid using the word “I”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems logical and rational, but it’s actually a real skill that needs to be developed in order to go beyond a personal opinion when giving feedback. Why? Because&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Saying “I don’t like this” or “I think that” omits actionable feedback and makes it become a personal statement. Of course we can’t disagree with someone’s personal perspective: it’s theirs, and not wrong from where they’re sitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removing “I” shifts the focus from the personal opinion and onto the rationale:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By removing “I” from your communication and focusing more on sharing rationale, your feedback becomes more concrete, more informative, and better suited for a collaborative context.
Instead of saying “I think this layout won’t work,” you could say: “Consider how this will translate from portrait to landscape and how that change might affect the constraints.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a skill I picked up from my painting teacher when I lived in Sweden. I sucked at painting but had a good grasp of aesthetic principles. Every lesson we would critique each others work and our teacher would push us to go beyond opinion and to focus on why. The result is rationale based feedback and actionable ideas. Things get better from this kind of feedback, where as opinion just wears you down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@tannerc/why-you-should-leave-i-out-of-feedback-9c78b0346264#.5jdg12ic9&quot;&gt;Why You Should Leave I Out of Feedback&lt;/a&gt; by Tanner Christensen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/qtNGHh&quot;&gt;Nice feedback system PC World&lt;/a&gt; by waldopepper CC-BY-NC&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 11:37:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2016/09/29/Leave-I-Out-of-Feedback.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2016/09/29/Leave-I-Out-of-Feedback.html</guid>
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
        <category>feedback</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>critque</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fewer instructions, better structures</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I stumbled across this post from Ewan McIntosh and found that it echoed quite a lot of my recent thoughts on designing for learning. I’m a huge proponent of the idea of creating an “engaging experience, first and foremost”, but all to often in education the focus is on curriculum-filling exercises and content. Maybe because it’s the easy way out, maybe it’s what we’re used to. Maybe we’re just too stuck on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Banking_education&quot;&gt;banking model of education&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goals Ewan provides are summarised here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encourage people to design experiences, not lessons.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encourage people to speak less.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Producers and educators could experiment with concentrating first and foremost on quality of engagement and experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Producers and educators should invest more their time empathising, observing and asking young people what makes them tick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a difference between instruction and structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really interested in the idea of exploring structure at the moment - something I hope I can do more of in the future. I think there are new possibilities if we look at transforming the structures of education rather than focussing on the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://edu.blogs.com/edublogs/2011/05/fewer-instructions-better-structures.html&quot;&gt;Fewer instructions, better structures&lt;/a&gt; by Ewan McIntosh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/6L1qwF&quot;&gt;Montreal Biosphère&lt;/a&gt; by Harald CC-BY-SA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 13:37:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2016/09/19/fewer-instructions-better-structures.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2016/09/19/fewer-instructions-better-structures.html</guid>
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>structure</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The World Wide Cage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is taken from &lt;em&gt;Utopia Is Creepy: And Other Provocations&lt;/em&gt; by Nicholas Carr, at it just that – provocative. I agree with a lot of what Carr outlines in this piece and it is a provocation to rethink the history and making of the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology as a religion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The greatest of the United States’ homegrown religions – greater than Jehovah’s Witnesses, greater than the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints, greater even than Scientology – is the religion of technology. John Adolphus Etzler, a Pittsburgher, sounded the trumpet in his testament The Paradise Within the Reach of All Men (1833). By fulfilling its ‘mechanical purposes’, he wrote, the US would turn itself into a new Eden, a ‘state of superabundance’ where ‘there will be a continual feast, parties of pleasures, novelties, delights and instructive occupations’, not to mention ‘vegetables of infinite variety and appearance’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reitterated by Marc Andreessen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 2014, the venture capitalist Marc Andreessen sent out a rhapsodic series of tweets – he called it a ‘tweetstorm’ – announcing that computers and robots were about to liberate us all from ‘physical need constraints’. Echoing Etzler (and Karl Marx), he declared that ‘for the first time in history’ humankind would be able to express its full and true nature: ‘we will be whoever we want to be.’ And: ‘The main fields of human endeavour will be culture, arts, sciences, creativity, philosophy, experimentation, exploration, adventure.’ The only thing he left out was the vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culture of the web:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The culture that emerged on the network, and that now extends deep into our lives and psyches, is characterised by frenetic production and consumption – smartphones have made media machines of us all – but little real empowerment and even less reflectiveness. It’s a culture of distraction and dependency. That’s not to deny the benefits of having easy access to an efficient, universal system of information exchange. It is to deny the mythology that shrouds the system. And it is to deny the assumption that the system, in order to provide its benefits, had to take its present form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The idea of the computer network as an engine of liberation is an innocent fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/the-internet-as-an-engine-of-liberation-is-an-innocent-fraud&quot;&gt;The World Wide Cage&lt;/a&gt; by Nicholas Carr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/D8jV3A&quot;&gt;Blue-Macaw&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Klapdor CC-BY-NC&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 13:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2016/09/13/world-wide-cage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2016/09/13/world-wide-cage.html</guid>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        <category>fraud</category>
        
        <category>surveillance</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaponized Transparency</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just finished listening to the latest episode of Audrey Watters and Kin Lane’s fantastic &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.techgypsi.es/blog/&quot;&gt;Tech Gypsies Podcast&lt;/a&gt;. The latest, &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.techgypsi.es/2016/07/31/episode-16&quot;&gt;Episode 16: Weaponized Transparency&lt;/a&gt;, deals with one of the biggest events that have surfaced in the past week. While the &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/read/all-signs-point-to-russia-being-behind-the-dnc-hack&quot;&gt;DNC Hack&lt;/a&gt; may sound like local and minor event, it demonstrates a new wave of international and state sponsored espionage. The use of hacking and releasing that data to intervene in a political process. Aside from the Hack itself is the role that WikiLeaks played in this, and as Audrey points out, this wasn’t a leak, this was theft. Break, enter and steal in it’s digital guise. Once the poster child of an open and transparent democracy Assange has led it down a dark path. Maybe a couple of years holed up in an Ecuadorian embassy will do that to you, but WikiLeaks is now operating as an asset of the Russian state. The vibrant idealism of openness and transparency has now faded to a beige of “rights” with no sense of responsibility or purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the last hour contemplating this concept of Weaponized Transparency. It’s such an apt description of what WikiLeaks has become and where Transparency has been taken. What doesn’t mean and where does it come from? How does something like Transparency become weaponised?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Maciej Ceglowski has noted, we are now in the grip of &lt;a href=&quot;http://idlewords.com/talks/sase_panel.htm&quot;&gt;Surveillance Capitalism&lt;/a&gt; and we are in the throes of the commoditisation is our privacy. Mined and manufactured, privacy is the new oil and it’s worth going to war for. In a war over privacy is it any wonder that Transparency has becomes weaponized?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data has no worth once it has become ubiquitous. The next wave of the Internet of Things will only prove that. Sure, there was an attempt to make data valuable again by packaging it up and renaming it “Big Data”, but that didn’t last long. Big Data is just noise. Sure there maybe a signal in there somewhere, but as a commodity it is the same as buying a radio to listen to the static. Today it’s the &lt;em&gt;absence of data that is of value&lt;/em&gt;. Privacy encapsulates that, and why exposing, leaking, doxing, stealing, hacking - making data available, making it transparent - is the new weapon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all boils down to money. This is all just another way of extracting value through the creation of a commodity. Extracting value regardless of the consequences. Fuck the forest, fuck the city, fuck the ecosystem, fuck the planet - and fuck the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://podcast.techgypsi.es/2016/07/31/episode-16&quot;&gt;Episode 16: Weaponized Transparency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/a7bhCM&quot;&gt;Through the Drinking Glass (1)&lt;/a&gt; by Ze’ev Barkan CC-BY&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 21:20:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2016/08/02/weaponised-transparency.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2016/08/02/weaponised-transparency.html</guid>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
        <category>tech gypsy</category>
        
        <category>transparency</category>
        
        <category>weaponised</category>
        
        <category>surveillance</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why High-Skilled Freelancers Are Leaving Corporate Life Behind</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some interesting perspectives in this article about work in the knowledge economy (as opposed to the industrial).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of the “comprehensivist”, and it relates to the kinds of terms I’ve used to describe myself - expert generalist and technopedagogue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However what I fail to see as the link between this kind of role and the “gig economy”. Yes coincidental in terms of timing but I don’t see them as linked. The rise of the comprehensivist is to do with the transition to a knowledge economy, the gig economy is symptomatic of the death throes of the industrial economy - squeezing every last dollar from labour before they splutter and die. A “If I go down, you’re going down with me” approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The section title “The Future Perfect” is pretty worrisome. It points to 4 Key limitations that have apparently been overcome:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;productivity&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;networking&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;safety nets&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;cultural limitations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would argue that none of these limitations have been actually been overcome. They’ve been “solutionised” - but certainly not solved. Rather a bandaid has been put in place that supports those with high amounts of capital - financial, social and cultural - to overcome them to a point, but are they fixed? Far from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’ll take from this is a new term - “comprehensivist” - and a reminder that there’s a lot of serious change required to reinvent a society for a knowledge based economy, and we have yet to even begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/3059898/the-future-of-work/how-high-skilled-freelancers-are-changing-the-rules-recruiting&quot;&gt;Why High-Skilled Freelancers Are Leaving Corporate Life Behind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/6L1qwF&quot;&gt;Montreal Biosphère&lt;/a&gt; by Harald CC-BY-SA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 23:25:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2016/05/31/comprehensivist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2016/05/31/comprehensivist.html</guid>
        
        <category>labour</category>
        
        <category>knowledge economy</category>
        
        <category>comprehensivist</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do I Own My Domain If You Grade It?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post from Andrew Rikard, a student from Davidson College is one the most insightful that I’ve read in some time. I had the pleasure of meeting Andrew on a recent trip and am a huge fan of his advocacy of the student voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a huge fan of the Domain of One’s Own project - something I think all universities can benefit from - but it’s interesting how little is heard from students directly on the topic. In this post Andrew calls into question, not the motive but the benefit that can be gained by working in this space without changes to curriculum and the ways we measure and reward “learning” in higher ed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I agree that owning data has the potential to give students agency and control. But it is not a guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I want to shift the emphasis from data possession to knowledge production. Gaining ownership over the data is vital—but until students see this domain as a space that rewards rigor and experimentation, it will not promote student agency. Traditional assignments don’t necessarily empower students when they have to post them in a public space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While concepts like Students as Producers are vital in changing the idea of assessment, it’s important that what is produced and created is meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting question is whether assignments - and hence things like ePortfolios - actually represent a student, their identity and passions? Does putting these assignments in public and attaching value to them in this way actually counteract agency?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew wraps up this post highlighting what Domain of Ones Own really represents:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The domains project isn’t revolutionary to the traditional classroom, but it is revolutionary to a classroom reimagined around public scholarship, student agency and experimentation. It makes sense when students find ownership in what they choose to create, how they put it online, and how it engages a broader audience. The question bigger than data ownership is how to make ownership over ideas happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edsurge.com/news/2015-08-10-do-i-own-my-domain-if-you-grade-it&quot;&gt;Do I Own My Domain If You Grade It?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/nYDz37&quot;&gt;construction-clouds-reflecting-on-glass-and-windows&lt;/a&gt; by ahlea CC0&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 06:40:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2016/04/27/Do-I-Own-My-Domain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2016/04/27/Do-I-Own-My-Domain.html</guid>
        
        <category>Domain of Ones Own</category>
        
        <category>student agency</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IMAP as the Proto Personal Cloud</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This older post got a retweet from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.windley.com/&quot;&gt;Phil Windley&lt;/a&gt; today and it reminded me of how awesome the web is, and how f*cking smart many of the people who work on it are. I’ve been reading through most of Phil’s recent posts and know of the work he’s pursing at BYU. I’m quite jealous to be honest but so happy that he’s sharing their work, and maybe more importantly, the thinking behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post discusses the underlying protocols that power one of the most widely used online technologies - email. IMAP and SMTP have not only made email possible but done so in a way that has made it possible for an ecosystem of applications to be created which has spurned new features and innovation that have resulted in email becoming the backbone for many organisations to actually function. But rather than do this by becoming a monopoloy and decimating the competition they were simply open Protocols. I think we’ve forgotten about protocols in tech. The focus seems to be on applications - applications that depend on open protocols to function, but which operate as their own islands. Email was not this at all, as Phil puts it so well””&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;email was designed with the architecture of the Internet in mind. Email is &lt;em&gt;decentralized&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;protocol-mediated&lt;/em&gt;. Email is &lt;em&gt;open&lt;/em&gt; —not necessarily open-source but open in that anyone can build clients and servers that speak IMAP and SMTP. As a result, &lt;strong&gt;email maximizes freedom and control for the user and minimizes the chance of disruption&lt;/strong&gt;. The features and benefits that email provides are exactly the same as those we want for personal clouds. Designed right, any application built on a personal cloud would provide similar functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve bolded that line in particular because I share that vision for the personal cloud - or &lt;a href=&quot;https://timklapdor.wordpress.com/2015/06/16/make-your-own-slogan-myos/&quot;&gt;MYOS&lt;/a&gt; as I’ve come to call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So perhaps what MYOS should be is not a technology stack - but a set of protocols. Perhaps the real innovation is in developing the protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also love his critique of Web 2.0 - and interestingly uses the phrase that kicked off my work on the topic last year - &lt;a href=&quot;https://timklapdor.wordpress.com/2015/08/13/you-are-not-in-control/&quot;&gt;You Are Not in Control&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Web 2.0 has given us a model that is exactly the opposite of email. The model encourages user data to be stored in separate silos. You cannot easily migrate from one service provider to another. And when a service provider goes away, you are abandoned and marooned. You are &lt;em&gt;not in control&lt;/em&gt;. Of course, it doesn’t help that this is all in the service provider’s best interest. They make money from the fact that the predominant model for building online applications leaves their users powerless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m starting to think that we went down the rabbit hole with Web 2.0 and are only now coming back into the light. Web 2.0 addressed something the Web hadn’t really tackled - the User Experience. It simplified getting online, creating, authoring and sharing and it’s been incredibly successful in that mission. But it sacrificed (almost literally on the altar) the distributed nature of the web to achieve it. What seems to be emerging now though is a desire to reclaim that aspect of the web. To reinvigorate the underlying network and explore the  protocols and conventions required to imagine the web we want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the greatest innovations in the next 5 years are not going to be in platforms or applications but in protocols and conventions. The web has worked becasue it can oscilate between the Wild West and Cooperative. It needs to get together again, just as it did in the web standards movement, to start thinking about the foundations were building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.windley.com/archives/2013/04/imap_as_the_proto_personal_cloud.shtml&quot;&gt;IMAP as the Proto Personal Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/e6sbn4&quot;&gt;Clouds&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Klapdor CC-BY-NC&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 18:05:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2016/01/31/IMAP-as-the-proto-personal-cloud.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2016/01/31/IMAP-as-the-proto-personal-cloud.html</guid>
        
        <category>IMAP</category>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        <category>MYOS</category>
        
        <category>email</category>
        
        <category>protocol</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tacit Knowledge Acquisition and Dissemination in Distance Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t normally link to one of Downes’ posts - seems weird to comment on commentary - but I really like that he pulled together another reference and this phrase sparked something:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Or maybe - as I think - all knowledge is tacit knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a throw away line and something that you can read more in the rest of Stephen’s work but it’s quite an interesting concept. It’s one I’ve been toying around with - especially as a backlash against the idea that knowledge can be divorced from people. That by collecting snippets of people’s knowledge as bits of text and articles and then placing it into a database you’ve somehow capture that knowledge rather than just captured abstracted information. And that once you’ve accumulated enough information you’ve somehow got knowledge at your fingertips rather than it becoming something that has become so abstracted it has to be sorted, sifted and instead practice operates more like raw data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s something I tried to capture in this diagram:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/article_images/knowledge-information-data.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Knowledge/Information/Data Cycle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s why simply having a library or access to a library or even working in a library doesn’t make you smarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.downes.ca/post/64825&quot;&gt;Tacit Knowledge Acquisition and Dissemination in Distance Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/Ay3nhr&quot;&gt;Knowledge Is Golden&lt;/a&gt; by Alan Grinberg CC-BY-ND&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 14:40:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2016/01/25/tacit-knowledge-acquisition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2016/01/25/tacit-knowledge-acquisition.html</guid>
        
        <category>tacit</category>
        
        <category>knowledge</category>
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
        <category>distance</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacking the City</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article discuss the work of Marcus Westbury and his attempt to revitalise the dying heart of the city of Newcastle, Australia. Westbury’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://renewnewcastle.org/&quot;&gt;Renew Newcastle&lt;/a&gt; project saw the run down central part of the city get a breath of air and come spluturing back to life. Having been to Newcastle during the down time I can attest to the The Walking Dead-esque nature of that part of town. But by using some fairly unconventional methods - such as utilising vacant spaces rent free - the town has come roaring back to life. This is an interesting tale of a post-industrial steel city bought to it knees as the mills closed. It’s also one of hope and the power of local action and utilising the global power of the web. Much of Westbury’s success has been because of the export of products enabled by the web. In this way new money is injected into the local community rather than borrowing it from somewhere else. This new money is the most crucial element and why many similar projects fail when they simply invest money and don’t generate anything new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my desire to work on local Civitas during 2016 this post has given me some really good ideas and inspired me to think that change is possible - especially if you focus on creating the infrastructure for the community to create the change themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/124470/hacking-city&quot;&gt;Hacking the City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/e6s7Rx&quot;&gt;New York by Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Klapdor CC-BY-NC&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 14:15:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/article/2016/01/25/hacking-the-city.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/article/2016/01/25/hacking-the-city.html</guid>
        
        <category>city</category>
        
        <category>hack</category>
        
        <category>newcastle</category>
        
        <category>free</category>
        
        
        <category>article</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>There’s a blockchain for that!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting read on what might be possible with the blockchain. There’s some interesting ideas in here - and a few that I tought were left unexplored. In particular the idea of a blockchain based identity management system - a decentralised passport for your online identity (I made a comment on the post if you want to join in). The kind of thing that Mozilla’s Persona never became.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The area of potential for big change via the blockchain is in the financial sector. The article notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A blockchain-powered economy is most likely to take root far away from the U.S., many observers believe — either in the developing world, where there’s less of a reliable financial system in place, or in places where property rules and contract law have shaky foundations (think Russia or China). Wherever it starts to take off, it will face the twin hurdles of complexity overload and government pushback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the uptake of mobile transactions in Africa I’d say that this is perhaps a more likely location. Companies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/M-Pesa&quot;&gt;M-Pesa&lt;/a&gt; rapidly grew because they took advantage of the abundance of simple mobile phones, coverage and a banking system that didn’t service the public. At the same time the lack of trust in the financial systems in the West might make it a likely breeding ground for this kind of system to be taken up. If someone comes up with a more localised system - one that worked within a community for simple trade and bypassed the cut that “middleman” models of Mastercard and Visa take you might be onto a winner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But perhaps it’s Maciej Ceglowski’s thoughts that are the most interesting…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There is a tendency in computer-land to seek technical solutions to political problems,” Ceglowski says. “In my opinion, the focus on the blockchain (and related ideas) falls into that misguided category. The idea that we should look to algorithms and technology to reclaim our freedoms is fundamentally undemocratic. It presupposes a technical elite who would ‘fix the Internet’ for everyone else. While I can see how this appeals to romantic ideas of hacking the system, I see it as a dangerous trend at worst, and a distraction at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We are terrible at predicting the social outcomes of technological innovation. There’s no reason Bitcoin-like distributed systems would be immune from that rule. I say let’s wise up and actually fight this battle on the level where it belongs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My feelings: I think Maciej is right - technology itself won’t fix anything &lt;strong&gt;on it’s own&lt;/strong&gt;. But technology can be a player, an enabler, an infrastructure on which to build change. Building technology that doesn’t rely on centralised control enables very different systems and applications to emerge. Decentralised systems undermine centralised control and erode their power structures. It’s the beginning of something bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/backchannel/how-bitcoins-blockchain-could-power-an-alternate-internet-bb501855af67#.ce49wbabr&quot;&gt;There’s a blockchain for that!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blockchaintechnologies.com/blockchain-definition&quot;&gt;Blockchain Consensus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 23:35:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/article/2016/01/21/theres-a-blockchain-for-that.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/article/2016/01/21/theres-a-blockchain-for-that.html</guid>
        
        <category>blockchain</category>
        
        
        <category>article</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
