<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inhales</title>
    <description>Captured breath from the Digital World
</description>
    <link>http://inhal.es/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://inhal.es/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 11:33:00 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 11:33:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Shit Knife</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This story comes from a wonderful talk from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daviswade.com&quot;&gt;Wade Davis&lt;/a&gt; that formed the second half of this podcast from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/radionational/programs/bigideas/when-factories-close_-ancient-wisdom/6810052&quot;&gt;Big Ideas&lt;/a&gt;. The ideas presented as ancient wisdom confirm a lot of my beliefs about the nature of culture but one part of the lecture really stood out to me – the &amp;quot;shit knife&amp;quot;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Inuit didn’t fear the cold; they took advantage of it. During the 1950s the Canadian government forced the Inuit into settlements. A family from Arctic Bay told me this fantastic story of their grandfather who refused to go. The family, fearful for his life, took away all of his tools and all of his implements, thinking that would force him into the settlement. But instead, he just slipped out of an igloo on a cold Arctic night, pulled down his caribou and sealskin trousers, and defecated into his hand. As the feces began to freeze, he shaped it into the form of an implement. And when the blade started to take shape, he put a spray of saliva along the leading edge to sharpen it. That’s when what they call the “shit knife” took form. He used it to butcher a dog. Skinned the dog with it. Improvised a sled with the dog’s rib cage, and then, using the skin, he harnessed up an adjacent living dog. He put the shit knife in his belt and disappeared into the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Shit Knife&amp;quot; is such a wonderful metaphor &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a video of that story (you can also watch the rest of the lecture if audio doesn&amp;#39;t do it for you). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XuJsbjKKh3E?t=36m04s&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Walrus_hunting.jpg#/media/File:Walrus_hunting.jpg&quot;&gt;Walrus Hunting&lt;/a&gt; CC0 (public domain)  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 11:07:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/podcast/2015/11/17/the-shit-knife.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/podcast/2015/11/17/the-shit-knife.html</guid>
        
        <category>indigenous</category>
        
        <category>stories</category>
        
        <category>ingenuity</category>
        
        <category>practice</category>
        
        <category>advantage</category>
        
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Web Annotations with Doug Schepers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After constant sync issues with Apple&amp;#39;s Podcast app I&amp;#39;ve jumped over to Marco Arments Overcast. It provides a nice alternative to iTunes for browsing and finding new podcasts and it&amp;#39;s how I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://thewebahead.net/&quot;&gt;The Web Ahead&lt;/a&gt;. I browsed the whole listing and cherry picked quite a few older episodes that struck my fancy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Episode 60: Web Annotations with Doug Schepers is a fantastic listen. Doug speaks with such passion about web annotations and highlights how it is the missing link in the webs current architecture. Commenting could be replaced by a specific annotation service. And it&amp;#39;s this service structure that makes the topic interesting - particularly when thought of through a distributed and federated framework. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you were empowered to comment, highlight, note, link to, compare and discuss on any site via your own infrastructure, your own service. That instead of feeding your comments into someone else&amp;#39;s system (and their business model) that you were able to share and syndicate that information. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is it the actual annotations that are interesting, but the threads possible to create through the web. Linking sites, pages, sections and quotes from across the web. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all fits my &lt;a href=&quot;https://timklapdor.wordpress.com/2015/07/28/the-quiet-page-linking-the-web/&quot;&gt;layered page metaphor&lt;/a&gt; and making this a web standard would allow this to not only possible, but ubiquitous. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/+I_4LuVpI&quot;&gt;Web Annotations with Doug Schepers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/7Pm7to&quot;&gt;Anotations Finnegans Wake&lt;/a&gt;by Karl Steel&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/podcast/2015/08/22/Web-Annotations-with-Doug-Schepers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/podcast/2015/08/22/Web-Annotations-with-Doug-Schepers.html</guid>
        
        <category>annotation</category>
        
        <category>highlighting</category>
        
        <category>commenting</category>
        
        <category>transclusion</category>
        
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Egyptian Lingerie and the Robot Future</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is what scares me about all the predictions of AI, Automation and post-labour:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panic over automation misses the real problem — that workers themselves are treated like machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Frase articulates something more incidious than losing jobs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I fear most is not that all of our labor will be replaced with machines. Rather, like Yglesias, I worry that it won’t be — but for a slightly different reason. Again, bosses prefer workers to machines when they are cheaper and easier to control. Hence the truly dystopian prospect is that the worker herself is treated as if she were a machine, rather than being replaced by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the future that frightens me. Not the rise of the machines, but the supplication of the people. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jacobinmag.com/2015/08/new-yorker-lingerie-automation-frase/&quot;&gt;Egyptian Lingerie and the Robot Future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/5rkS6R&quot;&gt;Robots (10)&lt;/a&gt; by Andreas. CC BY-NC-ND 2.0&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 12:10:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/article/2015/08/09/robot-future.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/article/2015/08/09/robot-future.html</guid>
        
        <category>labour</category>
        
        <category>robots</category>
        
        <category>labor</category>
        
        <category>automation</category>
        
        
        <category>article</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Healing Brain</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An extremely interesting and thought provoking interview with Norman Doidge, author of &lt;em&gt;The Brain&amp;#39;s Way Of Healing&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Brain That Changes Itself&lt;/em&gt;. The concept of neural plasticity is changes the way we need to conceptualise not just the brain, but biology as a whole. Its the first real demonstration that I&amp;#39;ve seen where complex systems are actually integrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d recommend this podcast (and by proxy the book) to anyone interested or connected to anyone dealing with neuralogical issues - strokes through to autism. It provides a reasoned argument for rethinking the way we tread these conditions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I got out of this talk was two important concepts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That the secret to the brain is understanding that it is an energy system. That it responds, controls, manipulates and translates energy in order for us to function. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The concept of a &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transducer&quot;&gt;transducer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; - a device that converts one form of energy to another form of energy. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transducer concept is particularly important in many of the treatments that Doidge describes. By delivery energy in one from - visual, auditory, sensory - it can be converted into other energy forms. These can then &amp;quot;treat&amp;quot; the various conditions of the brain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an introduction this is a great listen - Doidge is engaging and enthusiastic and capable of weaving a great narrative. For me it&amp;#39;s also kick started some thinking around energy and this concept of the transducer, a totally new term to me, but one that I can relate a lot of things too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/radionational/programs/bigideas/the-healing-brain/6643520&quot;&gt;The Healing Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/4wdEnR&quot;&gt;Ask the Brain&lt;/a&gt; by Thomas Hawk. CC-BY-NC&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 11:15:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/podcast/2015/08/08/the-healing-brain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/podcast/2015/08/08/the-healing-brain.html</guid>
        
        <category>brain</category>
        
        <category>plasticity</category>
        
        <category>transducer</category>
        
        <category>healing</category>
        
        <category>energy</category>
        
        <category>power</category>
        
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Gave Up Alternating Current</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I picked this post up from &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/&quot;&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt; and have to say that I feel the same as John Gruber - I can’t tell whether this is parody or not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read this as I am actually interesting in the concept of ditching Alternating for Direct Current. A return to localised power production via solar and wind would make sense for the more efficient DC standard and reduce the astounding amount of power wasted in transimission and conversion from AC. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that bit was interesting. The rest is an insight into a very alternate (maybe alien) lifestyle. Some of it makes sense, but often choices seem to contradict each other and the logic seems convoluted. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting adn intriguing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S. - the author of the post was the inventor of the food replacement - Soylent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://robrhinehart.com/?p=1331&quot;&gt;How I Gave Up Alternating Current&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/nrYkLp&quot;&gt;Soylent Green&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Lile&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 22:08:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/08/05/gave-up-alternating-current.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/08/05/gave-up-alternating-current.html</guid>
        
        <category>DC</category>
        
        <category>AC</category>
        
        <category>alternate</category>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>soylent</category>
        
        <category>power</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Denominator Problem: Understanding the Rising Cost of Human Attention</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is just 24 hours long. Tomorrow will be 24 hours long, too. We sleep an average of 7.7 hours a night, which leaves 16.3 hours in which we humans can pay attention to, well, everything. That’s not increasing. So, in other words — no matter how much we think we can multitask, human attention is finite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this take on time, attention and how it all relates to the information overload endemic in society. Rather than focus on people having to develop skills and practices in order to filter content, maybe we could actually start looking at the over production. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an observation I&amp;#39;d add that advertising is becoming increasingly meaningless. It noise that&amp;#39;s forcing different business models to emerge that no longer depend on ads to support them. Think Netflix. Think Spotify. Perhaps the next big thing coming, which I&amp;#39;ll be curious to see how plays out, is the fact that iOS 9 has native support to TURN OFF website ads. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we actually break down the fixed time in the day it forces us to rethink what it is we are trying to achieve in that space:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep: 7.5 hours (I’ll round down)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;School/Work: 8 hours (Let’s say the kids do very little, if any homework)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other: 2 hours (Socializing, drinking, video games, playing sports, texting, showering, brushing your teeth, talking to family…)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is 17.5 hours a day taken up by, well, living and stuff. So if every other waking second was spent consuming long and short form video — which it isn’t — that would only be 6.5 hours per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other idea in this piece that I can really relate to is a definition of time as a finite asset. One that we can and should measure &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; , rather than something to measure &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt;. I have a huge issue with time as a measurement of anything - because it&amp;#39;s relative and far more complex. Seat time, labour hours - they&amp;#39;re proxies that are becoming more and more redundant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it&amp;#39;s time to re-think time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/denominator-problem-understanding-rising-cost-human-joe-marchese&quot;&gt;The Denominator Problem: Understanding the Rising Cost of Human Attention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/96bybq&quot;&gt;Brighton Clock Tower&lt;/a&gt; by Dominic Alves&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:44:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/08/05/denominator-problem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/08/05/denominator-problem.html</guid>
        
        <category>time,content,advertising,attention,denominator</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blackboard’s Complexity Problems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Interesting take on the latest news from Blackboard. The comments perhaps are the best bit of the article - and where the most cogent points are made. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty telling point  that resonates with my experience with most large scale technology projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackboard has chosen its strategy with Ultra. But by putting it off for so long there is now a lot of major work to be done instead of a steady stream of less risky changes/improvements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than ongoing and iterative updates, improvements and pruning you end up with something colossal that takes a massive amount of effort to change. Despite the rise of agile in development circles, it&amp;#39;s yet to make its way into the &amp;quot;Business As Usual&amp;quot; teams. And management? Fuhgeddaboudit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://edutechnica.com/2015/08/01/blackboards-complexity-problems/&quot;&gt;Blackboard’s Complexity Problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/69125796@N00/7420991330&quot;&gt;Teaching Chemistry&lt;/a&gt; by starmanseries shared under a Creative Commons (BY) license&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 14:24:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/08/04/bbs-complexity-problem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/08/04/bbs-complexity-problem.html</guid>
        
        <category>Blackboard</category>
        
        <category>LMS</category>
        
        <category>complexity</category>
        
        <category>versions</category>
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
        <category>iteration</category>
        
        <category>incremental</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MOOCs, MIT and Magic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Great write up from Tony Bates from a recent conference at MIT. It provides a great overview of some of the topics covered during the talks, and also provides a really interesting overview of the structures and history of online learning and teaching at MIT. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his final observations he makes a couple of key points that I think apply to most  higher education institutions (and perhaps explains why online learning has been so bad for so long). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIT is still tied though to the lecture as the main means of delivery for online learning. In fact, the MIT students on the panel showed that they understand the need to adopt a different approach to online learning better than the faculty. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a fan of the lecture as a format - but not for ongoing teaching. Lectures should be seen as an effective  content delivery mechanism but it&amp;#39;s use should be limited. It should augment actual engagement with students, not be the form of engagement. Which perhaps says a lot about the next point too (emphasis added). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MOOCs are the consequence of lecture capture technology. This technology makes it easy to move teaching online, but without changing the design of the teaching. This usually results in &lt;strong&gt;information transmission becoming the primary pedagogy&lt;/strong&gt;, without addressing the many limitations of lectures, except the ability for asynchronous access, which is an important improvement on the ‘live’ lecture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information transmission is what I often refer to as Content First design and its what&amp;#39;s holding back higher education from really improving its overall learning and teaching practices. There&amp;#39;s a historic reason for this, the scarcity of information and knowledge, but that&amp;#39;s what the internet has changed. Instead we have information abundance which completely devalues and obsoletes information transmission as a primary pedagogy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tonybates.ca/2013/06/26/moocs-mit-and-magic/&quot;&gt;MOOCs, MIT and Magic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: photo credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/81295370@N00/211020203&quot;&gt;Science vacation&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;http://photopin.com&quot;&gt;photopin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&quot;&gt;(license)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 10:41:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/08/01/MOOCs-MIT-and-Magic.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/08/01/MOOCs-MIT-and-Magic.html</guid>
        
        <category>MOOC</category>
        
        <category>MOOCs</category>
        
        <category>online</category>
        
        <category>teaching</category>
        
        <category>MIT</category>
        
        <category>Bates</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Today’s march is a challenge to the rule of money</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This quote was linked to from Richard Hall&amp;#39;s post &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.richard-hall.org/2015/04/14/on-rage-against-learning-gain/&quot;&gt;on [rage against] learning gain&lt;/a&gt; which is a collection of quotes and snippets around the metrics being used in Higher Education. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular quote from John Holloway just stood out in stark contrast and immediately drew me in. It&amp;#39;s such a deep and insightful observation on the role of money in our social structure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we rage against the rule of money. Not against money itself, necessarily, because in the present society we need money to live. We rage rather against the rule of money, against a society in which money dominates. Money is a great bulldozer tearing up the world. It is an insidious force penetrating ever more aspects of our lives. Money holds society together, but it does so in a way that tears it apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one stage it seemed we had pushed the rule of money back, at least in areas like health and education. It was never really so, and for a long time we have seen the progressive re-imposition of the rule of money as the prime criterion for every decision. Now money has emerged in all its arrogance. That is what makes us so angry – the government has proclaimed openly “Money is king, bow low to the king!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rage, then, rage against the rule of money! As long as money rules, injustice and violence prevail – money is the breach between the starving and the food, the gap between the homeless and the houses. As long as money rules we are trapped in a dynamic that nobody controls and that is visibly destroying the possibility of human existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money seems all powerful, yet it is not. It is merely a form of social cohesion, and depends on our compliance. Say no, then. Do something else, do things in a different way. Refuse and create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– John Holloway. 2011. Today’s march is a challenge to the rule of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2011/mar/26/protest-rule-of-money&quot;&gt;Today’s march is a challenge to the rule of money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/pagedooley/3302646512&quot;&gt;Paper money&lt;/a&gt; by Kevin Dooley shared under a Creative Commons (BY) license&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 19:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/quote/2015/07/31/rule-of-money.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/quote/2015/07/31/rule-of-money.html</guid>
        
        <category>money</category>
        
        <category>rule</category>
        
        <category>rage</category>
        
        <category>cohesion</category>
        
        
        <category>quote</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Web We Have to Save</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having spent 6 years in Evin prison in northern Tehran,  this post from Hossein Derakhshan provides a unique perspective of the web and how it&amp;#39;s changed in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hyperlink was my currency six years ago. Stemming from the idea of the hypertext, the hyperlink provided a diversity and decentralisation that the real world lacked. The hyperlink represented the open, interconnected spirit of the world wide web — a vision that started with its inventor, Tim Berners-Lee. The hyperlink was a way to abandon centralization — all the links, lines and hierarchies — and replace them with something more distributed, a system of nodes and networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[...] Since I got out of jail, though, I’ve realized how much the hyperlink has been devalued, almost made obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rise of mobile and the &amp;quot;app&amp;quot; container it introduced has changed the way most people think about and interact with internet technologies. Now when most people discuss the web it&amp;#39;s through the lens of an app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypertext was, and still is, a quite radical way of approaching text. Our cultural traditions have embedded a &lt;em&gt;linear structure&lt;/em&gt; as the norm. The hyperlink disrupts that cultural narrative and for many people it&amp;#39;s uncomfortable so the contained app makes more sense to them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hossein&amp;#39;s observations about social media are really quite interesting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, these social networks tend to treat native text and pictures — things that are directly posted to them — with a lot more respect than those that reside on outside web pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps a sign of the &amp;quot;enclosure of the web&amp;quot; and the establishment of the Vectoral Class? Well maybe...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centralization of information also worries me because it makes it easier for things to disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the scariest outcome of the centralization of information in the age of social networks is something else: It is making us all much less powerful in relation to governments and corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I think this observation is pretty spot on. Despite the ability for the internet to engage and create spaces for real and meaningful interaction it isn&amp;#39;t. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web was not envisioned as a form of television when it was invented. But, like it or not, it is rapidly resembling TV: linear, passive, programmed and inward-looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/matter/the-web-we-have-to-save-2eb1fe15a426&quot;&gt;The Web We Have to Save&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/pFwRbV&quot;&gt;White House Vigil To Save Net Neutrality 11&lt;/a&gt; from Stephen Melkisethian&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 08:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/30/web-to-save.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://inhal.es/post/2015/07/30/web-to-save.html</guid>
        
        <category>hyperlink</category>
        
        <category>link</category>
        
        <category>centralised</category>
        
        <category>centralized</category>
        
        <category>reading</category>
        
        <category>television</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
